<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Amazon on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/amazon/</link><description>Recent content in Amazon on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 01:26:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/amazon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Securing Your Code With Amazon Q Developer 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/secure-coding-with-amazon-q/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/secure-coding-with-amazon-q/</guid><description>Securing Your Code With Amazon Q Developer Introduction
What is Amazon Q Developer? Amazon Q Developer is a generative artificial intelligence (AI) powered conversational assistant that can help us understand, build, extend, and operate AWS applications. We can ask questions about AWS architecture, our AWS resources, best practices, documentation, support, and more. Amazon Q is constantly updating its capabilities so our questions get the most contextually relevant and actionable answers. How Amazon Q Developer help us with secure coding?</description></item><item><title>Integrate Jfrog Artifactory with AWS Managed workflow for Apache Airflow 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrate-jfrog-with-amwa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrate-jfrog-with-amwa/</guid><description>Integrate Jfrog Artifactory with AWS Managed workflow for Apache Airflow Overview
When managing data pipelines and workflows in AWS Managed Apache Airflow, it&amp;rsquo;s often necessary to integrate with various external services for tasks such as downloading binaries, libraries, or other dependencies. JFrog Artifactory is a popular binary repository manager that allows you to securely store and manage artifacts. Integrating JFrog with AWS Managed Apache Airflow enables seamless and secure downloading of these artifacts, ensuring that your workflows can reliably access the necessary resources.</description></item><item><title>Integrate AWS Secret Manager with AWS Managed workflow for Apache Airflow 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrate-secret-with-amwa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrate-secret-with-amwa/</guid><description>Integrate AWS Secret Manager with AWS Managed workflow for Apache Airflow Overview
What is AWS Managed Apache Airflow?
AWS Managed Apache Airflow (MWAA) is a managed service that makes it easier to run and manage workflows built with Apache Airflow on AWS. Apache Airflow is an open-source tool used to programmatically author, schedule, and monitor workflows. With MWAA, AWS takes care of the operational aspects such as scaling, patching, and availability, allowing you to focus on building and managing your workflows.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Bedrock Agent - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-agent/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-agent/</guid><description>Amazon Bedrock Agent - Overview Introduction
What is Amazon Bedrock?
Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies like Stability AI, Anthropic, and Meta via a single API. It also provides the broad capabilities needed to build Generative AI applications with security, privacy, and responsible AI. Since Amazon Bedrock is serverless, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to manage any infrastructure, and you can securely integrate and deploy Generative AI capabilities into your applications using the AWS services you already know.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-kb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-kb/</guid><description>Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases - Overview Introduction
What is Amazon Bedrock? Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies like Stability AI, Anthropic, and Meta via a single API. It also provides the broad capabilities needed to build Generative AI applications with security, privacy, and responsible AI. Since Amazon Bedrock is serverless, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to manage any infrastructure, and you can securely integrate and deploy Generative AI capabilities into your applications using the AWS services you already know.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Lightsail - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-lightsail/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-lightsail/</guid><description>Amazon Lightsail - Overview Introduction
What is Amazon Lightsail?
Amazon Lightsail is the easiest way to get started with Amazon Web Services (AWS) for anyone who needs to build websites or web applications. It includes everything you need to launch your project quickly—instances (virtual private servers), container services, managed databases, content delivery network (CDN) distributions, load balancers, SSD-based block storage, static IP addresses, DNS management of registered domains, and resource snapshots (backups) - for a low, predictable monthly price.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Redshift ML - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-rs-serverless-ml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-rs-serverless-ml/</guid><description>Amazon Redshift ML - Overview Introduction
Amazon Redshift ML makes it easy for data analysts and database developers to create, train, and apply machine learning models using familiar SQL commands in Amazon Redshift data warehouses.
With Redshift ML, you can take advantage of Amazon SageMaker, a fully managed machine learning service, without learning new tools or languages. Simply use SQL statements to create and train Amazon SageMaker machine learning models using your Redshift data and then use these models to make predictions.</description></item><item><title>How to scale Spark jobs via Karpenter with Amazon EMR on Amazon EKS?💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-on-eks-karpenter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-on-eks-karpenter/</guid><description>How do you run Spark jobs with Amazon EMR on Amazon EKS?💡 Introduction
Amazon EMR on EKS provides a deployment option for Amazon EMR that allows you to run open-source big data frameworks on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS).
With this deployment option, you can focus on running analytics workloads while Amazon EMR on EKS builds, configures, and manages containers for open-source applications.
The following diagram shows the two different deployment models for Amazon EMR.</description></item><item><title>How do you run Flink job with Amazon EMR on Amazon EKS?💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-on-eks-flink/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-on-eks-flink/</guid><description>How do you run Flink jobs with Amazon EMR on Amazon EKS?💡 Introduction
Amazon EMR on EKS provides a deployment option for Amazon EMR that allows you to run open-source big data frameworks on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS).
With this deployment option, you can focus on running analytics workloads while Amazon EMR on EKS builds, configures, and manages containers for open-source applications.
The following diagram shows the two different deployment models for Amazon EMR.</description></item><item><title>How do you run Spark jobs with Amazon EMR on Amazon EKS?💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-on-eks-spark/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-on-eks-spark/</guid><description>How do you run Spark jobs with Amazon EMR on Amazon EKS?💡 Introduction
Amazon EMR on EKS provides a deployment option for Amazon EMR that allows you to run open-source big data frameworks on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS).
With this deployment option, you can focus on running analytics workloads while Amazon EMR on EKS builds, configures, and manages containers for open-source applications.
The following diagram shows the two different deployment models for Amazon EMR.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring and Security of Amazon Redshift DataShares 💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part4/</guid><description>Monitoring and Security of Amazon Redshift DataShares Introduction
What is Amazon Redshift Data Sharing?
Amazon Redshift Data Sharing is a feature that enables Redshift cluster owners to share live data across different Amazon Redshift clusters, accounts, and regions. With data sharing, users can easily and securely share data with other Redshift users, without having to copy or move the data. What are Amazon Redshift Data Sharing Benefits?
Data sharing is a great way to improve your security and performance, as well as save money.</description></item><item><title>Permissions Management for Amazon Redshift DataShares 💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part3/</guid><description>Permissions Management for Amazon Redshift DataShares What is Amazon Redshift Data Sharing?
Amazon Redshift Data Sharing is a feature that enables Redshift cluster owners to share live data across different Amazon Redshift clusters, accounts, and regions. With data sharing, users can easily and securely share data with other Redshift users, without having to copy or move the data. What are Amazon Redshift Data Sharing Benefits?
Data sharing is a great way to improve your security and performance, as well as save money.</description></item><item><title>Perform Workload Isolation using Amazon Redshift Data Sharing 💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part2/</guid><description>Perform Workload Isolation using Amazon Redshift Data Sharing Introduction
What is Amazon Redshift Data Sharing?
Amazon Redshift Data Sharing is a feature that enables Redshift cluster owners to share live data across different Amazon Redshift clusters, accounts, and regions. With data sharing, users can easily and securely share data with other Redshift users, without having to copy or move the data. What are Amazon Redshift Data Sharing Benefits?
Data sharing is a great way to improve your security and performance, as well as save money.</description></item><item><title>Seamless Data Sharing Using Amazon Redshift 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part1/</guid><description>Seamless Data Sharing Using Amazon Redshift Introduction
What is Amazon Redshift?
Amazon Redshift is a fast, fully managed, petabyte-scale cloud-based data warehouse service. It makes it simple and cost-effective to efficiently run your analytics workloads at scale. Amazon Redshift uses columnar storage (also known as columnstore) to store your data in columns instead of rows, which allows it to make more efficient use of storage space and compute resources than traditional row-oriented databases like MySQL or PostgreSQL.</description></item><item><title>Orchestration Amazon EMR Serverless using MWAA⏰</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/orchestration-emr-serverless-mwaa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/orchestration-emr-serverless-mwaa/</guid><description>Orchestration Amazon EMR Serverless using Amazon Managed Workflows for Apache Airflow (MWAA) Introduction
What is Amazon EMR?
Amazon EMR is a cloud big data platform running large-scale distributed data processing jobs, interactive SQL queries, and machine learning (ML) applications using open-source analytics frameworks such as Apache Spark, Apache Hive, and Presto. Understanding clusters and nodes A cluster is a collection of Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances. An instance in the cluster is called a node, and each node has role within the cluster, referred to as the node type.</description></item><item><title>Amazon EMR Serverless - RDS Hive MetaStore Integration ⚒️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-serverless-hive-metastore/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-serverless-hive-metastore/</guid><description>Amazon EMR Serverless - RDS Hive MetaStore Integration Introduction
What is Amazon EMR?
Amazon EMR is a cloud big data platform running large-scale distributed data processing jobs, interactive SQL queries, and machine learning (ML) applications using open-source analytics frameworks such as Apache Spark, Apache Hive, and Presto. Understanding clusters and nodes A cluster is a collection of Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances. An instance in the cluster is called a node, and each node has role within the cluster, referred to as the node type.</description></item><item><title>Amazon EMR Serverless - Glue Hive MetaStore Integration ⚒️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-serverless-glue-metastore/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-serverless-glue-metastore/</guid><description>Amazon EMR Serverless - Glue Hive MetaStore Integration Introduction
What is Amazon EMR?
Amazon EMR is a cloud big data platform running large-scale distributed data processing jobs, interactive SQL queries, and machine learning (ML) applications using open-source analytics frameworks such as Apache Spark, Apache Hive, and Presto. Understanding clusters and nodes A cluster is a collection of Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances. An instance in the cluster is called a node, and each node has role within the cluster, referred to as the node type.</description></item><item><title>Amazon EMR Serverless - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-serverless/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-serverless/</guid><description>Amazon EMR Serverless - Overview Introduction
What is Amazon EMR?
Amazon EMR is a cloud big data platform running large-scale distributed data processing jobs, interactive SQL queries, and machine learning (ML) applications using open-source analytics frameworks such as Apache Spark, Apache Hive, and Presto. Understanding clusters and nodes A cluster is a collection of Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances. An instance in the cluster is called a node, and each node has role within the cluster, referred to as the node type.</description></item></channel></rss>