<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 01:26:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Securing Your Code With Amazon Q Developer 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/secure-coding-with-amazon-q/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/secure-coding-with-amazon-q/</guid><description>Securing Your Code With Amazon Q Developer Introduction
What is Amazon Q Developer? Amazon Q Developer is a generative artificial intelligence (AI) powered conversational assistant that can help us understand, build, extend, and operate AWS applications. We can ask questions about AWS architecture, our AWS resources, best practices, documentation, support, and more. Amazon Q is constantly updating its capabilities so our questions get the most contextually relevant and actionable answers. How Amazon Q Developer help us with secure coding?</description></item><item><title>Redshift Data Analysis with Generative SQL 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/rs-eda-genai/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/rs-eda-genai/</guid><description>Redshift Data Analysis with Generative SQL What is Amazon Redshift Serverless?
Amazon Redshift Serverless makes it convenient for you to run and scale analytics without having to provision and manage data warehouses. Amazon Redshift automatically provisions and scales data warehouse capacity to deliver fast performance for demanding and unpredictable workloads. You pay only for the capacity that you use. What is Amazon Q?
Amazon Q generates code, tests, debugs, and has multistep planning and reasoning capabilities that can transform and implement new code generated from developer requests.</description></item><item><title>Debugging Lambda Functions with Amazon Q 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/debug-lambda-amazon-q/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/debug-lambda-amazon-q/</guid><description>Debugging Lambda Functions with Amazon Q Introduction
What is AWS Lambda?
AWS Lambda is a serverless compute service that enables you to run applications and services without provisioning or managing servers. It automatically handles the underlying compute resources, allowing you to focus on your code and scale effortlessly. What is Amazon Q?
Amazon Q generates code, tests, debugs, and has multistep planning and reasoning capabilities that can transform and implement new code generated from developer requests.</description></item><item><title>Integrate Jfrog Artifactory with AWS Managed workflow for Apache Airflow 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrate-jfrog-with-amwa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrate-jfrog-with-amwa/</guid><description>Integrate Jfrog Artifactory with AWS Managed workflow for Apache Airflow Overview
When managing data pipelines and workflows in AWS Managed Apache Airflow, it&amp;rsquo;s often necessary to integrate with various external services for tasks such as downloading binaries, libraries, or other dependencies. JFrog Artifactory is a popular binary repository manager that allows you to securely store and manage artifacts. Integrating JFrog with AWS Managed Apache Airflow enables seamless and secure downloading of these artifacts, ensuring that your workflows can reliably access the necessary resources.</description></item><item><title>Integrate AWS Secret Manager with AWS Managed workflow for Apache Airflow 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrate-secret-with-amwa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrate-secret-with-amwa/</guid><description>Integrate AWS Secret Manager with AWS Managed workflow for Apache Airflow Overview
What is AWS Managed Apache Airflow?
AWS Managed Apache Airflow (MWAA) is a managed service that makes it easier to run and manage workflows built with Apache Airflow on AWS. Apache Airflow is an open-source tool used to programmatically author, schedule, and monitor workflows. With MWAA, AWS takes care of the operational aspects such as scaling, patching, and availability, allowing you to focus on building and managing your workflows.</description></item><item><title>Tips &amp; Tricks for Optimizing Amazon OpenSearch: Performance and Cost Efficiency 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-opensearch-best-practice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-opensearch-best-practice/</guid><description>Tips &amp;amp; Tricks for Optimizing Amazon OpenSearch: Performance and Cost Efficiency Amazon OpenSearch Service (formerly Amazon Elasticsearch Service) is a powerful tool for search, log analytics, and real-time application monitoring. However, as with any cloud service, improper management can lead to performance issues and unexpected costs. Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore best practices to get the most out of OpenSearch while keeping your costs under control.
Rightsizing Your Infrastructure
Instance Selection: Use the latest generation instance types.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Bedrock Agent - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-agent/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-agent/</guid><description>Amazon Bedrock Agent - Overview Introduction
What is Amazon Bedrock?
Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies like Stability AI, Anthropic, and Meta via a single API. It also provides the broad capabilities needed to build Generative AI applications with security, privacy, and responsible AI. Since Amazon Bedrock is serverless, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to manage any infrastructure, and you can securely integrate and deploy Generative AI capabilities into your applications using the AWS services you already know.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-kb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-kb/</guid><description>Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases - Overview Introduction
What is Amazon Bedrock? Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies like Stability AI, Anthropic, and Meta via a single API. It also provides the broad capabilities needed to build Generative AI applications with security, privacy, and responsible AI. Since Amazon Bedrock is serverless, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to manage any infrastructure, and you can securely integrate and deploy Generative AI capabilities into your applications using the AWS services you already know.</description></item><item><title>Achieving Data Governance on AWS 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/achieving-data-governance-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/achieving-data-governance-on-aws/</guid><description>Achieving Data Governance on AWS Summary of Part 1
In Part 1 of our blog, we explored the fundamental concepts of data governance and how to achieve it on AWS. We discussed the importance of data governance for digital business success, the key roles involved, and how to align data governance with business initiatives. We also covered a comprehensive model for data governance, focusing on understanding, curating, and protecting data using AWS tools and services.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Lightsail - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-lightsail/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-lightsail/</guid><description>Amazon Lightsail - Overview Introduction
What is Amazon Lightsail?
Amazon Lightsail is the easiest way to get started with Amazon Web Services (AWS) for anyone who needs to build websites or web applications. It includes everything you need to launch your project quickly—instances (virtual private servers), container services, managed databases, content delivery network (CDN) distributions, load balancers, SSD-based block storage, static IP addresses, DNS management of registered domains, and resource snapshots (backups) - for a low, predictable monthly price.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Data Governance and How to Achieve It on AWS 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/understanding-data-governance-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/understanding-data-governance-on-aws/</guid><description>Understanding Data Governance and How to Achieve It on AWS Introduction
What is Data Governance?
Data governance is the practice of managing data to ensure its availability, usability, integrity, and security within an organization. According to Gartner, by 2025, 80% of organizations seeking to scale digital businesses will fail because they do not take a modern approach to data and analytics governance. Data governance involves a set of processes, roles, policies, standards, and metrics that ensure the effective and efficient use of information to enable an organization to achieve its goals.</description></item><item><title>Speed Up Your Data Journey: Building with the AWS Data Solutions Framework 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-data-solutions-framework/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-data-solutions-framework/</guid><description>Speed Up Your Data Journey: Building with the AWS Data Solutions Framework Introduction
The cloud has revolutionized data management, offering on-demand scalability and a vast array of services for building robust data solutions. But navigating the complexities of AWS and architecting secure, efficient data pipelines can be time-consuming.
Unveiling the Framework&amp;rsquo;s Magic
Built on the AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK), DSF offers reusable constructs representing common data platform components like data lakes, data pipelines, and analytics environments.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Redshift ML - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-rs-serverless-ml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-rs-serverless-ml/</guid><description>Amazon Redshift ML - Overview Introduction
Amazon Redshift ML makes it easy for data analysts and database developers to create, train, and apply machine learning models using familiar SQL commands in Amazon Redshift data warehouses.
With Redshift ML, you can take advantage of Amazon SageMaker, a fully managed machine learning service, without learning new tools or languages. Simply use SQL statements to create and train Amazon SageMaker machine learning models using your Redshift data and then use these models to make predictions.</description></item><item><title>Taming the Data Beast: How GenAI Tackles Data Quality Issues 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-genai-dqm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-genai-dqm/</guid><description>Taming the Data Beast: How GenAI Tackles Data Quality Issues Introduction:
In the age of big data, the foundation of every impactful decision rests on one crucial element: quality data. Yet, data often arrives messy, incomplete, and inconsistent, plaguing modern data platforms with significant challenges. That&amp;rsquo;s where GenAI, the transformative power of Generative Artificial Intelligence, comes in, offering a beacon of hope in the battle for data integrity. Data Quality Issues: The Hydra We Face:</description></item><item><title>Keeping the Data Stream Clean with AWS 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-dqm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-dqm/</guid><description>Keeping the Data Stream Clean: How AWS Data Quality Solutions Power Diverse Applications Introduction:
In today&amp;rsquo;s data-driven world, the adage &amp;ldquo;garbage in, garbage out&amp;rdquo; rings truer than ever. The quality of your data directly impacts the accuracy, efficiency, and ultimately, the success of your analytics and application development endeavors.
Recognizing this crucial link, AWS offers a comprehensive suite of data quality solutions, empowering organizations across various industries to harness the true potential of their data assets.</description></item><item><title>How to scale Spark jobs via Karpenter with Amazon EMR on Amazon EKS?💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-on-eks-karpenter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-on-eks-karpenter/</guid><description>How do you run Spark jobs with Amazon EMR on Amazon EKS?💡 Introduction
Amazon EMR on EKS provides a deployment option for Amazon EMR that allows you to run open-source big data frameworks on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS).
With this deployment option, you can focus on running analytics workloads while Amazon EMR on EKS builds, configures, and manages containers for open-source applications.
The following diagram shows the two different deployment models for Amazon EMR.</description></item><item><title>How do you run Flink job with Amazon EMR on Amazon EKS?💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-on-eks-flink/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-on-eks-flink/</guid><description>How do you run Flink jobs with Amazon EMR on Amazon EKS?💡 Introduction
Amazon EMR on EKS provides a deployment option for Amazon EMR that allows you to run open-source big data frameworks on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS).
With this deployment option, you can focus on running analytics workloads while Amazon EMR on EKS builds, configures, and manages containers for open-source applications.
The following diagram shows the two different deployment models for Amazon EMR.</description></item><item><title>How do you run Spark jobs with Amazon EMR on Amazon EKS?💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-on-eks-spark/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-on-eks-spark/</guid><description>How do you run Spark jobs with Amazon EMR on Amazon EKS?💡 Introduction
Amazon EMR on EKS provides a deployment option for Amazon EMR that allows you to run open-source big data frameworks on Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS).
With this deployment option, you can focus on running analytics workloads while Amazon EMR on EKS builds, configures, and manages containers for open-source applications.
The following diagram shows the two different deployment models for Amazon EMR.</description></item><item><title>Embracing AWS Zero ETL for Enhanced Data-Driven Decision Making 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-zero-etl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-zero-etl/</guid><description>Embracing AWS Zero ETL for Enhanced Data-Driven Decision Making Introduction
In the modern data-centric world, swift and informed decision-making is crucial for business success. AWS (Amazon Web Services) provides an innovative solution to expedite data-driven decisions through its Zero ETL (Extract, Transform, Load) approach. This blog delves into the essence of Zero ETL, its benefits, and a practical example showcasing its role in expediting data-driven decisions. Understanding Zero ETL
Zero ETL represents a data integration method that forgoes the conventional ETL process, which typically involves extracting data from various sources, transforming it to a structured format, and loading it into a data warehouse for analysis.</description></item><item><title>GenAI Revolution: Dr. Swami's AWS re:Invent 2023 Keynote 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-reinvent-2023-keynote-swami/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-reinvent-2023-keynote-swami/</guid><description>GenAI Revolution: Dr. Swami&amp;rsquo;s AWS re:Invent 2023 Keynote Introduction:
The buzz around generative AI (Gen AI) is electric, and for good reason. This transformative technology promises to reshape industries, redefine work, and unleash a wave of unprecedented creativity. Dr. Swami Sivasubramanian&amp;rsquo;s keynote at AWS re:Invent 2023 shed light on this captivating future, showcasing how AWS is empowering customers to become co-creators in the Gen AI revolution. Symbiotic Relationship:
Dr. Sivasubramanian emphasizes the symbiotic relationship between data, Gen AI, and humans.</description></item><item><title>A Frugal Approach to Innovation: Dr. Werner's AWS re:Invent 2023 Keynote 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-reinvent-2023-keynote-werner/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-reinvent-2023-keynote-werner/</guid><description>A Frugal Approach to Innovation: Dr. Werner&amp;rsquo;s AWS re:Invent 2023 Keynote Introduction
The keynote address at AWS re:Invent 2023 by Dr. Werner Vogels, Amazon CTO, offered valuable insights for developers and architects building on the cloud. Vogels emphasized the importance of cost-efficiency and sustainability in modern systems, urging the audience to adopt the mindset of a &amp;ldquo;Frugal Architect.&amp;rdquo; This blog post summarizes key takeaways from the talk, providing actionable steps for building cost-effective and sustainable systems on AWS.</description></item><item><title>Reinventing the Future: Adam Selipsky's AWS re:Invent 2023 Keynote🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-reinvent-2023-keynote-adam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-reinvent-2023-keynote-adam/</guid><description>Reinventing the Future: Adam Selipsky&amp;rsquo;s AWS re:Invent 2023 Keynote Introduction:
AWS re:Invent 2023 wasn&amp;rsquo;t just a tech conference; it was a rallying cry for reinvention. CEO Adam Selipsky&amp;rsquo;s keynote wasn&amp;rsquo;t simply about new features and products, but about empowering businesses of all sizes to reimagine their future and unlock groundbreaking possibilities. With real-world examples and a clear vision for the future, Selipsky painted a picture of how AWS is becoming the engine of innovation across industries.</description></item><item><title>AWS re:Invent 2023: A Glimpse into the Future of Cloud Computing and AI 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-reinvent-2023-announcement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-reinvent-2023-announcement/</guid><description>AWS re:Invent 2023: A Glimpse into the Future of Cloud Computing and AI AWS re:Invent 2023 has left an indelible mark on the cloud computing and artificial intelligence landscape. These announcements cover a wide range of services, including AI, machine learning, database management, cloud services, and more. The event showcased a plethora of groundbreaking announcements that are not just technological advancements but are set to redefine how businesses leverage cloud capabilities.</description></item><item><title>Unlocking the Full Potential of AWS re:Invent 2023 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-reinvent-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-reinvent-2023/</guid><description>Unlocking the Full Potential of AWS re:Invent 2023 1. Introduction:
AWS re:Invent 2023, hosted by Amazon Web Services (AWS), stands as a pinnacle event in cloud computing. Since its inception in 2012, it has showcased the forefront of cloud technology. This comprehensive guide aims to assist attendees, whether they&amp;rsquo;re seasoned cloud experts or just embarking on their AWS journey, in making the most of the multifaceted experience at AWS re:Invent 2023.</description></item><item><title>Overview of Amazon Athena for Apache Spark 💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-athena-spark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-athena-spark/</guid><description>Overview of Amazon Athena for Apache Spark Introduction
Amazon Athena for Apache Spark provides interactive analytics under a second to analyze petabytes of data using open source spark framework. Interactive Spark applications start instantly and run faster with our optimized Spark runtime, so you spend more time on insights, not waiting for results. Build Spark applications using the expressiveness of Python with a simplified notebook experience in an Athena console or through Athena APIs.</description></item><item><title>Tips &amp; Tricks while working on Amazon Redshift 🛡️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/tips-tricks-redshift/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/tips-tricks-redshift/</guid><description>Tips &amp;amp; Tricks while working on Amazon Redshift Introduction
Amazon Redshift, known for its scalability and efficiency, provides a powerful solution for data warehousing. This post offers a comprehensive technical exploration of Amazon Redshift, discussing best practices and examples about table design, query performance, cluster management, cost control, data sharing, data governance and security.
Table Design
Distribution Styles:
Redshift supports EVEN, KEY, and ALL distribution styles. The appropriate distribution style, which governs how data gets distributed across nodes, can significantly impact query performance.</description></item><item><title>Key Considerations for Utilizing Amazon Kinesis Producer and Consumer Libraries🛡️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/kinesis-library-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/kinesis-library-best-practices/</guid><description>Key Considerations for Utilizing Amazon Kinesis Producer and Consumer Libraries Introduction
As real-time data processing becomes increasingly critical in modern tech ecosystems, AWS Kinesis Data Streams (KDS) has emerged as a go-to solution. Kinesis offers scalable and durable real-time data streaming, further complemented by two crucial libraries:
Kinesis Producer Library (KPL) and Kinesis Consumer Library (KCL). Additionally, Kinesis supports advanced data sharing mechanisms, allowing data streams to be consumed by multiple entities simultaneously.</description></item><item><title>How to set up a secure Terraform backend using Amazon S3 + DynamoDB? 🛡️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/best-practice-terraform-backend/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/best-practice-terraform-backend/</guid><description>How to set up a secure Terraform backend using Amazon S3 + DynamoDB Introduction
Managing infrastructure as code is crucial for modern DevOps practices, and Terraform has emerged as a powerful tool for achieving this. In this technical guide, we will delve into the best practices for configuring a Terraform backend using Amazon Web Services&amp;rsquo; S3 bucket and associated resources. Our aim is to equip you with the skills needed to establish a production-ready environment with sensible defaults.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring and Security of Amazon Redshift DataShares 💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part4/</guid><description>Monitoring and Security of Amazon Redshift DataShares Introduction
What is Amazon Redshift Data Sharing?
Amazon Redshift Data Sharing is a feature that enables Redshift cluster owners to share live data across different Amazon Redshift clusters, accounts, and regions. With data sharing, users can easily and securely share data with other Redshift users, without having to copy or move the data. What are Amazon Redshift Data Sharing Benefits?
Data sharing is a great way to improve your security and performance, as well as save money.</description></item><item><title>Permissions Management for Amazon Redshift DataShares 💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part3/</guid><description>Permissions Management for Amazon Redshift DataShares What is Amazon Redshift Data Sharing?
Amazon Redshift Data Sharing is a feature that enables Redshift cluster owners to share live data across different Amazon Redshift clusters, accounts, and regions. With data sharing, users can easily and securely share data with other Redshift users, without having to copy or move the data. What are Amazon Redshift Data Sharing Benefits?
Data sharing is a great way to improve your security and performance, as well as save money.</description></item><item><title>Perform Workload Isolation using Amazon Redshift Data Sharing 💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part2/</guid><description>Perform Workload Isolation using Amazon Redshift Data Sharing Introduction
What is Amazon Redshift Data Sharing?
Amazon Redshift Data Sharing is a feature that enables Redshift cluster owners to share live data across different Amazon Redshift clusters, accounts, and regions. With data sharing, users can easily and securely share data with other Redshift users, without having to copy or move the data. What are Amazon Redshift Data Sharing Benefits?
Data sharing is a great way to improve your security and performance, as well as save money.</description></item><item><title>Seamless Data Sharing Using Amazon Redshift 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part1/</guid><description>Seamless Data Sharing Using Amazon Redshift Introduction
What is Amazon Redshift?
Amazon Redshift is a fast, fully managed, petabyte-scale cloud-based data warehouse service. It makes it simple and cost-effective to efficiently run your analytics workloads at scale. Amazon Redshift uses columnar storage (also known as columnstore) to store your data in columns instead of rows, which allows it to make more efficient use of storage space and compute resources than traditional row-oriented databases like MySQL or PostgreSQL.</description></item><item><title>Orchestration Amazon EMR Serverless using MWAA⏰</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/orchestration-emr-serverless-mwaa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/orchestration-emr-serverless-mwaa/</guid><description>Orchestration Amazon EMR Serverless using Amazon Managed Workflows for Apache Airflow (MWAA) Introduction
What is Amazon EMR?
Amazon EMR is a cloud big data platform running large-scale distributed data processing jobs, interactive SQL queries, and machine learning (ML) applications using open-source analytics frameworks such as Apache Spark, Apache Hive, and Presto. Understanding clusters and nodes A cluster is a collection of Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances. An instance in the cluster is called a node, and each node has role within the cluster, referred to as the node type.</description></item><item><title>Amazon EMR Serverless - RDS Hive MetaStore Integration ⚒️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-serverless-hive-metastore/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-serverless-hive-metastore/</guid><description>Amazon EMR Serverless - RDS Hive MetaStore Integration Introduction
What is Amazon EMR?
Amazon EMR is a cloud big data platform running large-scale distributed data processing jobs, interactive SQL queries, and machine learning (ML) applications using open-source analytics frameworks such as Apache Spark, Apache Hive, and Presto. Understanding clusters and nodes A cluster is a collection of Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances. An instance in the cluster is called a node, and each node has role within the cluster, referred to as the node type.</description></item><item><title>Apache Airflow - from Zero to Hero</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/apache-airflow-devtron/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/apache-airflow-devtron/</guid><description>Apache Airflow - from Zero to Hero Overview
In this webinar, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the factors to consider, the difficulties to overcome while running a custom Orchestration tool at scale, and how Apache Airflow comes to the rescue.
To begin, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss what it means to run Airflow at a large scale. The constructs of the Airflow architecture, Scheduler procedures, and configuration options will then be thoroughly discussed.
After that, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how Amazon Managed Workflows for Apache Airflow (MWAA) helps simplify the complexity of open-source Apache Airflow and the additional security features it offers.</description></item><item><title>Amazon EMR Serverless - Glue Hive MetaStore Integration ⚒️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-serverless-glue-metastore/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-serverless-glue-metastore/</guid><description>Amazon EMR Serverless - Glue Hive MetaStore Integration Introduction
What is Amazon EMR?
Amazon EMR is a cloud big data platform running large-scale distributed data processing jobs, interactive SQL queries, and machine learning (ML) applications using open-source analytics frameworks such as Apache Spark, Apache Hive, and Presto. Understanding clusters and nodes A cluster is a collection of Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances. An instance in the cluster is called a node, and each node has role within the cluster, referred to as the node type.</description></item><item><title>Amazon EMR Serverless - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-serverless/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-serverless/</guid><description>Amazon EMR Serverless - Overview Introduction
What is Amazon EMR?
Amazon EMR is a cloud big data platform running large-scale distributed data processing jobs, interactive SQL queries, and machine learning (ML) applications using open-source analytics frameworks such as Apache Spark, Apache Hive, and Presto. Understanding clusters and nodes A cluster is a collection of Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances. An instance in the cluster is called a node, and each node has role within the cluster, referred to as the node type.</description></item><item><title>Amazon VPC Network Access Analyzer 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-vpc-network-access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-vpc-network-access/</guid><description>Amazon VPC Network Access Analyzer Introduction
What is VPC Network Access Analyzer?
Network Access Analyzer is a feature that identifies unintended network access to your resources on AWS.
Understand, verify, and improve your network security posture: Network Access Analyzer helps you identify unintended network access relative to your security and compliance requirements, enabling you to improve your network security. Demonstrate compliance: You can use Network Access Analyzer to demonstrate that your network on AWS meets specific compliance requirements.</description></item><item><title>re:Wind 2022 📜</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/rewind-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/rewind-2022/</guid><description>re:Wind 2022 - A stepping stone, not a milestone. Summary
Every year in December, I create a list of my annual achievements vs. what I could have done better, self-retrospective. This helps me to establish my achievable goals and prevent myself from frustration.
2021 was an average year with the pandemic &amp;amp; work from home. I focused on most of the learning and established a constant routine between work, learning &amp;amp; community contribution.</description></item><item><title>Recap of AWS re:Invent 2022 - App Integration, Serverless &amp; DevSecOps Highlights 📜</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/reinvent2022-recap-devops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/reinvent2022-recap-devops/</guid><description>Recap of AWS re:Invent 2022 - App Integration, Serverless &amp;amp; DevSecOps Highlights Overview
AWS re:Invent 2022 is in the bag! The 11th iteration of the annual cloud conference saw more than 50,000 partners and customers descend on Las Vegas in person, accompanied by more than 300,000 remote attendees.
The world is asynchronous. The world is event-driven. — Dr. Werner Vogels, CTO, Amazon.com It required a world stage to propagate asynchrony and event-driven architecture in our modern era of cloud computing.</description></item><item><title>Recap of AWS re:Invent 2022 - Data &amp; Analytics Highlights 📜</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/reinvent2022-recap-dna/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/reinvent2022-recap-dna/</guid><description>Recap of AWS re:Invent 2022 - Data &amp;amp; Analytics Highlights Overview
AWS re:Invent 2022 is in the bag! The 11th iteration of the annual cloud conference saw more than 50,000 partners and customers descend on Las Vegas in person, accompanied by more than 300,000 remote attendees. The event featured excellent keynote speakers, product announcements, training and certification opportunities, hands-on technical sessions, and more. I was thrilled to witness all of the fun, fully embracing AWS CEO Adam Selipsky&amp;rsquo;s message that now is the perfect time to &amp;ldquo;lean in harder&amp;rdquo; to help clients accelerate their journey to the cloud.</description></item><item><title>AWS re:Invent 2022 - Reinvent your business with an AWS modern data strategy</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/aws-re-invent-2022---pex308/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/aws-re-invent-2022---pex308/</guid><description>AWS re:Invent 2022 - Reinvent your business with an AWS modern data strategy (PEX308) Overview
AWS can help organizations quickly get answers from data by providing mature and integrated analytics services ranging from cloud data warehouses to serverless data lakes. Join this session to learn about AWS modern data architecture and how AWS analytics services can help your customers navigate data challenges, optimize analytics processes, and deliver insights to their businesses faster.</description></item><item><title>Let's explore Apache Kafka, the Easy Way on AWS!</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/lets-explore-apache-kafka-the-easy-way-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/lets-explore-apache-kafka-the-easy-way-on-aws/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s explore Apache Kafka, the Easy Way on AWS! Overview
Apache Kafka is powerful. But &amp;ldquo;with great power, comes great responsibility&amp;rdquo;! Fortunately, with Amazon MSK, developers can focus on how to build with Kafka instead of being responsible for managing a large-scale distributed system.
This session will provide an overview of Amazon MSK (including its Serverless flavor) and MSK Connect. It will cover architecture along with hands-on demos to give you a better understanding of how to leverage Kafka on AWS to build practical solutions for everyday use cases.</description></item><item><title>Let's Code AWS CDK</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/lets-explore-aws-cdk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/lets-explore-aws-cdk/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Code AWS CDK Overview
&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s Code AWS CDK&amp;rdquo; which is The AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK), an open-source software development framework to define your cloud application resources using familiar programming languages.
We will cover the Flavors of CDK Construct, Creating CDK Project in Python, and Step-by-Step Deployment CDK project.
It is hosted by AWS UserGroup Mumbai to spread the knowledge of AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK)
Speakers.</description></item><item><title>AWS Summit India 2022 - Build a data lake with AWS Lake Formation</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/aws-summit-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/aws-summit-2022/</guid><description>AWS Summit India 2022 - Build a data lake with AWS Lake Formation Overview
Organisations are breaking down data silos and building petabyte-scale data lakes on AWS to democratise access to thousands of end users. Since its launch, AWS Lake Formation has accelerated data lake adoption by making it easy to build and secure data lakes.
In this session, we explore data lake challenges and how AWS Lake Formation can help you.</description></item><item><title>Serverless, No server, Really?</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/serverless-no-server-really/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/serverless-no-server-really/</guid><description>Serverless, No server, Really? Overview
AWS User Group Nashik-Mumbai-Pune is excited to announce our finale session as part of Serverless, No server, Really? series.
This session will explore other lesser-known serverless services that can help leverage the true power of serverless like Fargate, the difference between EC2 Fargate and Lambda, an overview of SAM, AWS Step Functions, AWS AppSync, Amazon EventBridge, Aurora Serverless, RDS Proxy, and much more.
Speakers.
Aishwarya Gupta - Senior Cloud Engineer, Quantiphi Jones Zachariah Noel N - AWS Serverless Hero &amp;amp; Sr.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with DevOps on AWS</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/getting-started-with-devops-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/getting-started-with-devops-on-aws/</guid><description>Getting Started with DevOps on AWS Overview
Getting Started with DevOps on AWS is a two part session for exploring different AWS services related to DevOps. It is hosted by AWS UserGroup Nashik to spread &amp;amp; aware the knowledge of DevOps. And it covers different AWS services like AWS CloudFormation AWS CodeCommit, CodePipeline, CodeDeploy Monitoring services - AWS CloudWatch Demo: To host static website on S3 using AWS CI/CD Demo: To deploy a LAMP stack using AWS CI/CD</description></item><item><title>Transform Data with AWS Glue DataBrew</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/transform-data-with-aws-glue-databrew/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/transform-data-with-aws-glue-databrew/</guid><description>Transform Data with AWS Glue DataBrew Overview
We all are fascinated with various analytical outcomes like different kinds of visualization. But do we know that 50% of the time is just spent cleansing, understanding, &amp;amp; exploring your data? Also, it is a combustion process, multiple iterations, time-consuming, etc.?
AWS launched the Glue DataBrew service to focus more on the business use-case and simplify the preparation activities. This session will focus on the Introduction of the Databrew service, different functionality, followed by a quick demo</description></item><item><title>Understanding Amazon EMR Serverless 🔋</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/emr-serverless/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/emr-serverless/</guid><description>Amazon EMR Serverless What is Amazon EMR?
Amazon EMR is a cloud big data platform for running large-scale distributed data processing jobs, interactive SQL queries, and machine learning (ML) applications using open-source analytics frameworks such as Apache Spark, Apache Hive, and Presto. Understanding clusters and nodes A cluster is a collection of Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances. Each instance in the cluster is called a node. Each node has a role within the cluster, referred to as the node type.</description></item><item><title>Discover insights for RDS using Amazon DevOps Guru 💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/devops-guru-rds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/devops-guru-rds/</guid><description>What is DevOps Guru for RDS?
DevOps Guru for RDS is a new ML-powered capability empowering developers and DevOps engineers to quickly detect, diagnose, and remediate a wide variety of database-related issues on Amazon RDS.
When DevOps Guru for RDS detects a database-related issue (such as resource overutilization, or misbehavior of certain SQL queries), the service immediately notifies you and provides diagnostic information, details on the extent of the problem, and intelligent recommendations to quickly resolve the issue.</description></item><item><title>Amazon S3 Intelligent-Tiering Archive Instant Access tier 🎚️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/s3-intelligent-tiering/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/s3-intelligent-tiering/</guid><description>Amazon S3 Intelligent-Tiering: Archive Instant Access tier What is Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3)?
Amazon S3 is one of the main building blocks of AWS. It&amp;rsquo;s advertised as&amp;quot; infinitely scaling&amp;quot; storage. It&amp;rsquo;s widely popular and deserves its section S3 provides unlimited storage space and works on the pay-as-you-use model. Service rates get cheaper as the usage volume increases Amazon S3 allows people to store objects (files) in &amp;ldquo;buckets&amp;rdquo; (directories). S3 resources, e.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3) Glacier Instant Retrieval 🎚️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/s3-glacier-instant-retrieval/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/s3-glacier-instant-retrieval/</guid><description>Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3) Glacier Instant Retrieval What is Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3)?
Amazon S3 is one of the main building blocks of AWS. It&amp;rsquo;s advertised as&amp;quot; infinitely scaling&amp;quot; storage. It&amp;rsquo;s widely popular and deserves its section S3 provides unlimited storage space and works on the pay-as-you-use model. Service rates get cheaper as the usage volume increases Amazon S3 allows people to store objects (files) in &amp;ldquo;buckets&amp;rdquo; (directories). S3 resources, e.</description></item><item><title>Overview of Amazon Modern Data Redshift Warehouse</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/overview-of-amazon-modern-data-redshift-warehouse/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/overview-of-amazon-modern-data-redshift-warehouse/</guid><description>Overview of Amazon Modern Data Redshift Warehouse Overview
Amazon Redshift uses SQL to analyze structured and semi-structured data across data warehouses, operational databases, and data lakes, using AWS-designed hardware and machine learning to deliver the best price performance at any scale.
This session will provide an overview of Amazon Redshift like overview, architecture, distribution keys and sort keys, Redshift spectrum, Advance feature, etc.
It is hosted by AWS UserGroup Mumbai to spread the knowledge of Amazon Modern Data Redshift Warehouse</description></item><item><title>Tracking Alerts Amazon S3 Event Notifications with Amazon EventBridge🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/s3-eventbridge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/s3-eventbridge/</guid><description>Amazon S3 Event Notifications with Amazon EventBridge What is Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3)?
Amazon S3 is one of the main building blocks of AWS. It&amp;rsquo;s advertised as&amp;quot; infinitely scaling&amp;quot; storage. It&amp;rsquo;s widely popular and deserves its section S3 provides unlimited storage space and works on the pay-as-you-use model. Service rates get cheaper as the usage volume increases Amazon S3 allows people to store objects (files) in &amp;ldquo;buckets&amp;rdquo; (directories). S3 resources, e.</description></item><item><title>Implement Custom Lenses for the AWS Well-Architected Tool 📝</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/custom-lens-war/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/custom-lens-war/</guid><description>Custom Lenses for the AWS Well-Architected Tool What is AWS Well-Architected?
The AWS Well-Architected Framework describes key concepts, design principles, and architectural best practices for designing and running workloads in the cloud.
AWS Well-Architected helps cloud architects build secure, high-performing, resilient, and efficient infrastructure for various applications and workloads.
Built around six pillars
Operational excellence, Security, Reliability, Performance efficiency, Cost optimization, and Sustainability AWS Well-Architected provides a consistent approach for customers and partners to evaluate architectures and implement scalable designs.</description></item><item><title>Build Amazon Container Image using AWS EC2 Image Builder ⚒️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-image-builder-pipeline-container/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-image-builder-pipeline-container/</guid><description>Container Image pipeline using AWS EC2 Image Builder Introduction
EC2 Image Builder is a wholly managed AWS service that simplifies the process to automate the creation, management, and deployment of tailored, secure, and up-to-date server images that are pre-installed and pre-configured with software and settings to match specific IT standards.
Features of EC2 Image Builder
Greater productivity and reduced operations for building compliant and up-to-date images The more excellent service uptime Improved the security standard for deployments Centralized enforcement and lineage tracking Simplified sharing of resources across AWS accounts How EC2 Image Builder works?</description></item><item><title>Build Amazon Ec2 Image using AWS EC2 Image Builder ⚒️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-image-builder-pipeline-ec2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-image-builder-pipeline-ec2/</guid><description>Ec2 Image pipeline using AWS EC2 Image Builder Introduction
EC2 Image Builder is a wholly managed AWS service that simplifies the process to automate the creation, management, and deployment of tailored, secure, and up-to-date server images that are pre-installed and pre-configured with software and settings to match specific IT standards.
Features of EC2 Image Builder
Greater productivity and reduced operations for building compliant and up-to-date images The more excellent service uptime Improved the security standard for deployments Centralized enforcement and lineage tracking Simplified sharing of resources across AWS accounts How EC2 Image Builder works?</description></item><item><title>AWS SAA-C02 Certification Bootcamp</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/aws-saa-co2-certification-bootcamp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/aws-saa-co2-certification-bootcamp/</guid><description>WALKTHROUGH OF THE WELL-ARCHITECTED TOOL Introduction
Top-rated certifications are a crucial factor to help you stand out in the crowded IT landscape, and with constant certification buzz on LinkedIn and other platforms, the AWS User Groups across multiple cities in India are collaborating to bring you the AWS Solution Architect Associate Training Bootcamp.
It is an initiative to promote and provide a forum for interested people to join and prepare for this certification to excel in their professional careers.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Amazon Layered Virtual Private Cloud Architecture 🛡️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-layered-vpc-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-layered-vpc-architecture/</guid><description>Introduction to Amazon Layered Virtual Private Cloud Architecture 1. Overview
This blog describes the basic Seven Layered network architecture. The following diagram shows the various components of the architecture; the VPC with two availability zones with several AWS Services, each of which is in place to support the organization within AWS Cloud. Each service has a high-level description in the sections below that provides an overview of that particular component. 2.</description></item><item><title>Exploring video transcoding on AWS using AWS Elemental Mediaconvert 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-elemental-mediaconvert/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-elemental-mediaconvert/</guid><description>AWS Elemental Mediaconvert Introduction
AWS Elemental MediaConvert is a file-based video transcoding service with broadcast-grade functionality. It offers to easily generate on-demand video (VOD) content for transmitting and multiscreen distribution at a larger scale.
The service merges advanced video and audio functionality via a UI with pay-as-you-go pricing. This service also allows for delivering compelling media experiences without having to worry about the criticality of building and operating your own video processing infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Exploring AWS Workflow Studio💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/introduction-aws-workflow-studio/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/introduction-aws-workflow-studio/</guid><description>AWS Step Function Introduction
What is Step Function?
AWS Step Function is a serverless orchestration service that allows integrating multiple AWS services to collate &amp;amp; design an enterprise-critical application or workflow with advance conditional branching and error handling
Step Functions provides sequencing, error handling, retry logic, state, and offers a visualization-driven method to organize and represent the series of event-driven steps of your application through its graphical console.
And makes it easier and simpler to build and execute multiple-state event-driven critical applications.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Drift detection in AWS Cloudformation 🚀</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/cloudformation-drift-detection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/cloudformation-drift-detection/</guid><description>Drift detection Introduction
Drift detection allows to identify either a stack&amp;rsquo;s actual configuration differs or has drifted, from its original deployed values. We can use CloudFormation to identify drift on an entire stack or resources within the stack
A resource is examined as drifted if its actual property values delta from the expected property values. This contains if the property or resource has been modified or deleted. A stack is considered to have drifted if one or more of its resources have drifted</description></item><item><title>Catalog Data using AWS Glue Data Catalog 📖</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-glue-data-catalog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-glue-data-catalog/</guid><description>Introduction Glue Data Catalog is an AWS native service that allows persisting, tag, and extends metadata in a similar fashion like an Apache Hive metastore. Every AWS account holds one AWS Glue Data Catalog in every region.
It offers a consistent store where multiple sources can persist and lookup metadata to organize the data and leverage it to query and transform the data.
Following are the additional extensions to Glue Data Catalog:</description></item><item><title>Let's explore the working of AWS Application Migration Service 📦</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-application-migration-service/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-application-migration-service/</guid><description>AWS Application Migration Service Introduction
AWS Application Migration Service allows migrating the critical workloads to AWS avoiding any interference, or data leakage. With continuous block-level replication, automated machine conversion, and application stack orchestration, Application Migration Service simplifies the migration process and minimizes the chance for human error.
Whether we are moving to AWS or across regions within AWS, Application Migration Service simplicity the needs and provides the security measures require to win in today’s fast-paced digital era</description></item><item><title>Build metrics on logs with AWS Cloudwatch Metrics 📊</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-cloudwatch-metrics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-cloudwatch-metrics/</guid><description>AWS Cloudwatch Metrics Introduction
Metrics are information around the performance of the systems.
Out of the box a few AWS services offer metrics at no cost for resources such as Ec2, EBS, and RDS. We can also switch to detailed monitoring for a couple of resources such as Ec2 to fetch more details around the performances, and the best thing is we can publish our own application metrics.
Amazon CloudWatch ingests all the metrics in the AWS account (both AWS resource metrics and application metrics) for searching, graphing, and alarms.</description></item><item><title>Exploring AWS App Runner 💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-app-runner/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-app-runner/</guid><description>Introduction of AWS App Runner Introduction
AWS App Runner is a service that offers a fast, simple, and cost-effective method to deploy a Github repository or a docker image as a web application in the AWS Cloud, and offers direct integration and delivery pipeline with fully managed operations, high performance, scalability, and security.
Out of the box, App Runner is built for the desired scale, so there is no requirement to re-platform or re-architect as the business grows and makes it simpler to rapidly deliver innovative solutions and business value, regardless of the language they are written in, even for teams that lack prior experience deploying and managing containers or infrastructure</description></item><item><title>Exploring Amazon Pinpoint💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-amazon-pinpoint/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-amazon-pinpoint/</guid><description>Amazon Pinpoint Introduction
Amazon Pinpoint is an AWS service which allow to occupy the customers across multiple messaging channels. We can leverage Amazon Pinpoint to send push notifications, emails, SMS text messages, and voice messages.
Amazon Pinpoint allows to send customer oriented messages with better experiences which strengths the association with the customers and reduce the agitate.
Amazon Pinpoint provides functionalities such as:
Marketing campaigns and journeys
Transactional messages
Analytics tools</description></item><item><title>Let's understand the tips to secure Amazon S3 buckets 🛡️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/security-of-aws-s3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/security-of-aws-s3/</guid><description>AWS S3 Security Introduction
Amazon S3 provides an optimal foundation because of its virtually unlimited scalability. You can seamlessly and non-disruptively increase storage from gigabytes to petabytes of content, paying only for what you use. Amazon S3 is designed to provide 99.999999999% durability.
It has scalable performance, ease-of-use features, and native encryption and access control capabilities. Amazon S3 integrates with a broad portfolio of AWS and third-party ISV data processing tools.</description></item><item><title>Configure AWS Managed Service For Grafana 📉</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-managed-grafana/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-managed-grafana/</guid><description>AWS Managed Service For Grafana Introduction
Amazon Managed Service for Grafana (AMG) is a completely managed service that allows defining query, relations, and depicts trends, logs, and traces for the applications from various sources like Amazon CloudWatch, Amazon Elasticsearch Service, Amazon Timestream, AWS IoT SiteWise, AWS X-Ray, and Amazon Managed Service for Prometheus (AMP) and provides plug-ins to popular open-source databases, third-party ISV monitoring tools, as well as other cloud services.</description></item><item><title>How to configure AWS SSO? 🔐</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/enable-aws-sso/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/enable-aws-sso/</guid><description>Enable AWS SSO Introduction
Access management across different AWS accounts is a complicated and painful task but now with AWS SSO, it is much easier and simple to handle such activities. In this tutorial, we will focus on configuring AWS SSO to simplify user management across multiple accounts based on their roles.
This tutorial is divided into sections
Switch AWS SSO for your organization Configure AWS SSO permission sets Configure AWS SSO groups Allocate groups to your accounts Customize your SSO endpoint Connect to the AWS Console using your SSO endpoint Tutorial</description></item><item><title>What is AWS Parameter Store? 🔑</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-parameter-store/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-parameter-store/</guid><description>AWS Systems Manager Parameter Store Introduction
AWS Systems Manager Parameter Store offers secure, hierarchical storage for configuration data management and secrets management. You can persist in things such as passwords, connection strings, Ec2 AMI IDs, and license as parameter values. Values can be persisted as plain text or encrypted data. You can refer to parameters in your scripts by providing the unique name that you mention while creating the parameter. How can Parameter Store benefit my organization?</description></item><item><title>Deep-dive of custom resources in AWS Cloudformation 📌</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/cloudformation-custom-resources/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/cloudformation-custom-resources/</guid><description>Cloudformation Custom resources What is AWS Cloudformation?
AWS CloudFormation offers an easy way to deploy a collection of related AWS and third-party resources, provision them faster, and manage them throughout their lifecycles, by treating infrastructure as code.
A CloudFormation template contains information for the desired resources and their dependencies so we can launch and configure them together as a stack. We can use templates to create, update, and delete an entire stack as a single unit, instead of managing resources individually.</description></item><item><title>Exploring AWS Application Discovery Service 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-application-discovery-service/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-application-discovery-service/</guid><description>AWS Application Discovery Service Introduction
AWS Discovery Agent is an AWS software that is deployed in any targeted servers like physical on-premises servers, Amazon EC2 instances, and virtual machines for discovery and migration. It captures information like system configuration, system performance, running processes, and details of the network connections between systems.
This agent required root privileges to collect the information. When you start the Discovery Agent, it registers with the Application Discovery Service endpoint, arsenal.</description></item><item><title>Tracking Alerts with Amazon EventBridge in a real-time way 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/alerting-with-eventbridge/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/alerting-with-eventbridge/</guid><description>Alerts with Amazon EventBridge Introduction
EventBridge bridges your application based on events. You can plug your own AWS platform with REST API, any SaaS applications, and custom apps as event sources that publish events to an event bus. You can state a filtering rule to refine events and target events to different services and REST endpoint destinations. EventBridge reduces the process of constructing an event-driven platform. EventBridge, decouple the destination from the source of the event, and this way you can refine and notify directly to EventBridge.</description></item><item><title>Query Insights from AWS CloudTrail Logs with AWS Athena 🔎</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrating-cloudtrail-logs-with-athena/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrating-cloudtrail-logs-with-athena/</guid><description>Fetch Insights from AWS CloudTrail Logs with Athena Introduction
Leveraging AWS Athena with CloudTrail logs is an impactful method to refine your insights of AWS service activity. For example, you can leverage queries to detect findings and further trace activity by attributes, like source IP address or user etc
Below are the steps we need to follow to implement this tutorial
Configure S3 bucket
Navigate to S3 console
Select Create bucket button</description></item><item><title>Generate Inventory of AWS resources using AWS Systems Manager 📝</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-inventory/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-inventory/</guid><description>AWS Systems Manager Inventory Introduction
AWS Systems Manager Inventory offers transparency to your Amazon EC2 and on-premises processing ecosystem. We can leverage Inventory to capture metadata from your managed instances Metadata generated from AWS Systems Manager Inventory can be persisted in an Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3) bucket and post you can query the data and identify the version of the software and different configuration deployed in your instance as per your organization software policy, and which instances need to be updated You can configure Inventory on all of your managed instances by a single-click process.</description></item><item><title>What is AWS Budget &amp; Report?💰</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-budget-and-report/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-budget-and-report/</guid><description>AWS Budget Monthly cost budget
Introduction
AWS Budgets provides a feature to handle cost and utilization by providing notifications when cost or usage is beyond the configured threshold. It can only be used as a mechanism to notify the usage and not a medium to restrict the actions. Budgets and notifications are directly dependent on your billing data and it is updated at least once a day NOTE: You may not receive an alarm for a forecasted budget if your account is new.</description></item><item><title>Tool to assist AWS Well-Architected Framework ⌛</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/walkthrough-of-war-tool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/walkthrough-of-war-tool/</guid><description>WALKTHROUGH OF THE WELL-ARCHITECTED TOOL Introduction
AWS Well-Architected Framework assists architects to create secure, scalable, durable, and efficient workload and it consists of five foundational pillars Operational Excellence, Security, Reliability, Performance Efficiency, and Cost Optimization It is a repeatable framework that assists customers and partners to validate the architectures and design that can scale over time. The AWS WA Tool, which is free at no cost and available under AWS Management Console, provides a way to regularly validate your workloads, discover potential issues, and capture your improvements.</description></item><item><title>How to deploy Grafana on Amazon Ec2? 🚀</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/deploy-grafana-ec2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/deploy-grafana-ec2/</guid><description>Deploy Grafana Introduction Grafana is open-source software famous for creating graphs and visualizations for end-users to articulate the time-series data. In this tutorial, we will focus on the following steps and it will carry out on an EC2 Instance with Amazon Linux 2 as the operating system
Provisioning Ec2 server Installation of Grafana Testing the setup Adding Data Source in the Grafana Testing CloudWatch as a Data Source Step 1 - Provisioning Ec2 server</description></item><item><title>Unboxing Tips for AWS security 🛡️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/security-best-practice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/security-best-practice/</guid><description>Ten AWS security tips
If you’re looking to improve your cloud security, an excellent place to start is to follow the top 10 most important cloud security tips that Stephen Schmidt, Chief Information Security Officer for AWS, laid out at AWS re:Invent 2019. Underneath represent the tips, expanded to aid you to take action.
Account information
Configure right contact info under AWS console management including the email address used to set up the account and those listed under Alternate Contacts.</description></item><item><title>Enable In-memory search using Amazon ElasticSearch Service 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-elasticsearch-service-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-elasticsearch-service-introduction/</guid><description>AWS ElasticSearch Service This article provides guidance on setting up an Elasticsearch cluster with Kibana on AWS (Amazon Web Services) cloud platform using CloudFormation. Also, it provides the user with instructions on how to access the cluster and Kibana endpoints.
Need for Elasticsearch and Use Cases
Elasticsearch is a managed AWS (Amazon Web Services) service for Log analytics and management. A common use case is Monitoring Infrastructure or Application Performance and assisting in failure diagnosis.</description></item><item><title>How to achieve message Filtering in Amazon SNS? 📨</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-sns-filtering/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-sns-filtering/</guid><description>MESSAGE FILTERING What is Amazon SNS Message Filtering?
By default, an Amazon SNS topic subscriber receives every message published to the topic. To receive a subset of the messages, a subscriber must assign a filter policy to the topic subscription. A filter policy is a simple JSON object containing attributes that define which messages the subscriber receives.
When you publish a message to a topic, Amazon SNS compares the message attributes to the attributes in the filter policy for each of the topic’s subscriptions.</description></item><item><title>Explore managed Kubernetes offering from AWS (AWS EKS)🚀</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-eks-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-eks-introduction/</guid><description>Introduction to Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service What is Amazon EKS?
Amazon EKS (Elastic Container Service for Kubernetes) is a managed Kubernetes service that allows you to run Kubernetes on AWS without the hassle of managing the Kubernetes control plane. The Kubernetes control plane plays a crucial role in a Kubernetes deployment as it is responsible for how Kubernetes communicates with your cluster The big benefit of EKS, and other similar hosted Kubernetes services, is taking away the operational burden involved in running this control plane.</description></item><item><title>How to deploy scheduled task in AWS Fargate? ⏰</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/scheduled-task-aws-fargate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/scheduled-task-aws-fargate/</guid><description>Create a scheduled task in AWS Fargate AWS Fargate
Fargate is a managed service for container orchestration provided by AWS. In ECS, we always need to provision the EC2 cluster first before running services. Also, there is an operating cost to maintain the cluster. When there is a change, we need to change both the underlying cluster (the number of EC2 instances) and services (the number of tasks). In Fargate, you don’t need to operate the cluster.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/readme/</guid><description>👋 Hi, I’m Sanchit Jain. Welcome to my blogfolio!
👀 I’m interested in AWS Cloud, Database &amp;amp; Analytics and Application Modernization.
💼 I’m currently working at Quantiphi, and Community contribution is my passion.
📫 How to reach me : connect@getsetbuild.cloud</description></item></channel></rss>