<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Genai on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/genai/</link><description>Recent content in Genai on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:15:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/genai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Amazon Bedrock Agent - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-agent/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-agent/</guid><description>Amazon Bedrock Agent - Overview Introduction
What is Amazon Bedrock?
Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies like Stability AI, Anthropic, and Meta via a single API. It also provides the broad capabilities needed to build Generative AI applications with security, privacy, and responsible AI. Since Amazon Bedrock is serverless, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to manage any infrastructure, and you can securely integrate and deploy Generative AI capabilities into your applications using the AWS services you already know.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-kb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-kb/</guid><description>Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases - Overview Introduction
What is Amazon Bedrock? Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies like Stability AI, Anthropic, and Meta via a single API. It also provides the broad capabilities needed to build Generative AI applications with security, privacy, and responsible AI. Since Amazon Bedrock is serverless, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to manage any infrastructure, and you can securely integrate and deploy Generative AI capabilities into your applications using the AWS services you already know.</description></item><item><title>Taming the Data Beast: How GenAI Tackles Data Quality Issues 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-genai-dqm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-genai-dqm/</guid><description>Taming the Data Beast: How GenAI Tackles Data Quality Issues Introduction:
In the age of big data, the foundation of every impactful decision rests on one crucial element: quality data. Yet, data often arrives messy, incomplete, and inconsistent, plaguing modern data platforms with significant challenges. That&amp;rsquo;s where GenAI, the transformative power of Generative Artificial Intelligence, comes in, offering a beacon of hope in the battle for data integrity. Data Quality Issues: The Hydra We Face:</description></item></channel></rss>