<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Webinars on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/</link><description>Recent content in Webinars on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Amazon S3 Intelligent-Tiering Archive Instant Access tier 🎚️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/s3-intelligent-tiering/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/s3-intelligent-tiering/</guid><description>Amazon S3 Intelligent-Tiering: Archive Instant Access tier What is Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3)?
Amazon S3 is one of the main building blocks of AWS. It&amp;rsquo;s advertised as&amp;quot; infinitely scaling&amp;quot; storage. It&amp;rsquo;s widely popular and deserves its section S3 provides unlimited storage space and works on the pay-as-you-use model. Service rates get cheaper as the usage volume increases Amazon S3 allows people to store objects (files) in &amp;ldquo;buckets&amp;rdquo; (directories). S3 resources, e.</description></item><item><title>Let's understand the tips to secure Amazon S3 buckets 🛡️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/security-of-aws-s3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/security-of-aws-s3/</guid><description>AWS S3 Security Introduction
Amazon S3 provides an optimal foundation because of its virtually unlimited scalability. You can seamlessly and non-disruptively increase storage from gigabytes to petabytes of content, paying only for what you use. Amazon S3 is designed to provide 99.999999999% durability.
It has scalable performance, ease-of-use features, and native encryption and access control capabilities. Amazon S3 integrates with a broad portfolio of AWS and third-party ISV data processing tools.</description></item><item><title>Tool to assist AWS Well-Architected Framework ⌛</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/walkthrough-of-war-tool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/walkthrough-of-war-tool/</guid><description>WALKTHROUGH OF THE WELL-ARCHITECTED TOOL Introduction
AWS Well-Architected Framework assists architects to create secure, scalable, durable, and efficient workload and it consists of five foundational pillars Operational Excellence, Security, Reliability, Performance Efficiency, and Cost Optimization It is a repeatable framework that assists customers and partners to validate the architectures and design that can scale over time. The AWS WA Tool, which is free at no cost and available under AWS Management Console, provides a way to regularly validate your workloads, discover potential issues, and capture your improvements.</description></item><item><title>Unboxing Tips for AWS security 🛡️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/security-best-practice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/security-best-practice/</guid><description>Ten AWS security tips
If you’re looking to improve your cloud security, an excellent place to start is to follow the top 10 most important cloud security tips that Stephen Schmidt, Chief Information Security Officer for AWS, laid out at AWS re:Invent 2019. Underneath represent the tips, expanded to aid you to take action.
Account information
Configure right contact info under AWS console management including the email address used to set up the account and those listed under Alternate Contacts.</description></item><item><title>How to deploy scheduled task in AWS Fargate? ⏰</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/scheduled-task-aws-fargate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/scheduled-task-aws-fargate/</guid><description>Create a scheduled task in AWS Fargate AWS Fargate
Fargate is a managed service for container orchestration provided by AWS. In ECS, we always need to provision the EC2 cluster first before running services. Also, there is an operating cost to maintain the cluster. When there is a change, we need to change both the underlying cluster (the number of EC2 instances) and services (the number of tasks). In Fargate, you don’t need to operate the cluster.</description></item></channel></rss>