<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Webinars on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/</link><description>Recent content in Webinars on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:56:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Airflow - from Zero to Hero</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/apache-airflow-devtron/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/apache-airflow-devtron/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="apache-airflow---from-zero-to-hero">Apache Airflow - from Zero to Hero&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In this webinar, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the factors to consider, the difficulties to overcome while running a custom Orchestration tool at scale, and how Apache Airflow comes to the rescue.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>To begin, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss what it means to run Airflow at a large scale. The constructs of the Airflow architecture, Scheduler procedures, and configuration options will then be thoroughly discussed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>After that, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how Amazon Managed Workflows for Apache Airflow (MWAA) helps simplify the complexity of open-source Apache Airflow and the additional security features it offers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AWS re:Invent 2022 - Reinvent your business with an AWS modern data strategy</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/aws-re-invent-2022---pex308/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/aws-re-invent-2022---pex308/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="aws-reinvent-2022---reinvent-your-business-with-an-aws-modern-data-strategy-pex308">AWS re:Invent 2022 - Reinvent your business with an AWS modern data strategy (PEX308)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>AWS can help organizations quickly get answers from data by providing mature and integrated analytics services ranging from cloud data warehouses to serverless data lakes. Join this session to learn about AWS modern data architecture and how AWS analytics services can help your customers navigate data challenges, optimize analytics processes, and deliver insights to their businesses faster. This session also includes customer case studies and a demo of a modern data platform using AWS analytics serverless services with real-world streaming data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Let's explore Apache Kafka, the Easy Way on AWS!</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/lets-explore-apache-kafka-the-easy-way-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/lets-explore-apache-kafka-the-easy-way-on-aws/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="lets-explore-apache-kafka-the-easy-way-on-aws">Let&amp;rsquo;s explore Apache Kafka, the Easy Way on AWS!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Apache Kafka is powerful. But &amp;ldquo;with great power, comes great responsibility&amp;rdquo;! Fortunately, with Amazon MSK, developers can focus on how to build with Kafka instead of being responsible for managing a large-scale distributed system.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>This session will provide an overview of Amazon MSK (including its Serverless flavor) and MSK Connect. It will cover architecture along with hands-on demos to give you a better understanding of how to leverage Kafka on AWS to build practical solutions for everyday use cases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Let's Code AWS CDK</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/lets-explore-aws-cdk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/lets-explore-aws-cdk/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="lets-code-aws-cdk">Let&amp;rsquo;s Code AWS CDK&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s Code AWS CDK&amp;rdquo; which is The AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK), an open-source software development framework to define your cloud application resources using familiar programming languages.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>We will cover the Flavors of CDK Construct, Creating CDK Project in Python, and Step-by-Step Deployment CDK project.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It is hosted by AWS UserGroup Mumbai to spread the knowledge of AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Speakers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AWS Summit India 2022 - Build a data lake with AWS Lake Formation</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/aws-summit-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/aws-summit-2022/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="aws-summit-india-2022---build-a-data-lake-with-aws-lake-formation">AWS Summit India 2022 - Build a data lake with AWS Lake Formation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Organisations are breaking down data silos and building petabyte-scale data lakes on AWS to democratise access to thousands of end users. Since its launch, AWS Lake Formation has accelerated data lake adoption by making it easy to build and secure data lakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In this session, we explore data lake challenges and how AWS Lake Formation can help you. If you&amp;rsquo;re a developer, DBA, or a data engineer who works with data, this session is for you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Serverless, No server, Really?</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/serverless-no-server-really/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/serverless-no-server-really/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="serverless-no-server-really">Serverless, No server, Really?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>AWS User Group Nashik-Mumbai-Pune is excited to announce our finale session as part of Serverless, No server, Really? series.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>This session will explore other lesser-known serverless services that can help leverage the true power of serverless like Fargate, the difference between EC2 Fargate and Lambda, an overview of SAM, AWS Step Functions, AWS AppSync, Amazon EventBridge, Aurora Serverless, RDS Proxy, and much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Speakers.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Aishwarya Gupta - Senior Cloud Engineer, Quantiphi&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Jones Zachariah Noel N - AWS Serverless Hero &amp;amp; Sr.Developer Advocate, Freshworks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Anurag Kale - AWS Data Hero &amp;amp; Cloud Software Architect, Polestar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Srushith Repakula - AWS Serverless Hero &amp;amp; Head of Engineering, KonfHub&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sanchit Jain - AWS Community Hero &amp;amp; Data Analytics &amp;amp; Cloud Practice Lead, Quantiphi&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Khi5jo1Zn5E">&lt;img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/Khi5jo1Zn5E/maxresdefault.jpg" alt="Watch the video">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting Started with DevOps on AWS</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/getting-started-with-devops-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/getting-started-with-devops-on-aws/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="getting-started-with-devops-on-aws">Getting Started with DevOps on AWS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Getting Started with DevOps on AWS is a two part session for exploring different AWS services related to DevOps.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It is hosted by AWS UserGroup Nashik to spread &amp;amp; aware the knowledge of DevOps. And it covers different AWS services like
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>AWS CloudFormation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>AWS CodeCommit, CodePipeline, CodeDeploy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Monitoring services - AWS CloudWatch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Demo: To host static website on S3 using AWS CI/CD&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Demo: To deploy a LAMP stack using AWS CI/CD&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/XdgXdzTxiII">&lt;img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/XdgXdzTxiII/maxresdefault.jpg" alt="Watch the video">&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Transform Data with AWS Glue DataBrew</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/transform-data-with-aws-glue-databrew/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/transform-data-with-aws-glue-databrew/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="transform-data-with-aws-glue-databrew">Transform Data with AWS Glue DataBrew&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>We all are fascinated with various analytical outcomes like different kinds of visualization. But do we know that 50% of the time is just spent cleansing, understanding, &amp;amp; exploring your data? Also, it is a combustion process, multiple iterations, time-consuming, etc.?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>AWS launched the Glue DataBrew service to focus more on the business use-case and simplify the preparation activities. This session will focus on the Introduction of the Databrew service, different functionality, followed by a quick demo&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overview of Amazon Modern Data Redshift Warehouse</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/overview-of-amazon-modern-data-redshift-warehouse/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/overview-of-amazon-modern-data-redshift-warehouse/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview-of-amazon-modern-data-redshift-warehouse">Overview of Amazon Modern Data Redshift Warehouse&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Amazon Redshift uses SQL to analyze structured and semi-structured data across data warehouses, operational databases, and data lakes, using AWS-designed hardware and machine learning to deliver the best price performance at any scale.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>This session will provide an overview of Amazon Redshift like overview, architecture, distribution keys and sort keys, Redshift spectrum, Advance feature, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It is hosted by AWS UserGroup Mumbai to spread the knowledge of Amazon Modern Data Redshift Warehouse&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AWS SAA-C02 Certification Bootcamp</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/aws-saa-co2-certification-bootcamp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/aws-saa-co2-certification-bootcamp/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="walkthrough-of-the-well-architected-tool">WALKTHROUGH OF THE WELL-ARCHITECTED TOOL&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Introduction&lt;/strong>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Top-rated certifications are a crucial factor to help you stand out in the crowded IT landscape, and with constant certification buzz on LinkedIn and other platforms, the AWS User Groups across multiple cities in India are collaborating to bring you the AWS Solution Architect Associate Training Bootcamp.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It is an initiative to promote and provide a forum for interested people to join and prepare for this certification to excel in their professional careers.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>