<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Devops on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in Devops on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 17:50:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started with DevOps on AWS</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/getting-started-with-devops-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/getting-started-with-devops-on-aws/</guid><description>Getting Started with DevOps on AWS Overview
Getting Started with DevOps on AWS is a two part session for exploring different AWS services related to DevOps. It is hosted by AWS UserGroup Nashik to spread &amp;amp; aware the knowledge of DevOps. And it covers different AWS services like AWS CloudFormation AWS CodeCommit, CodePipeline, CodeDeploy Monitoring services - AWS CloudWatch Demo: To host static website on S3 using AWS CI/CD Demo: To deploy a LAMP stack using AWS CI/CD</description></item><item><title>Discover insights for RDS using Amazon DevOps Guru 💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/devops-guru-rds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/devops-guru-rds/</guid><description>What is DevOps Guru for RDS?
DevOps Guru for RDS is a new ML-powered capability empowering developers and DevOps engineers to quickly detect, diagnose, and remediate a wide variety of database-related issues on Amazon RDS.
When DevOps Guru for RDS detects a database-related issue (such as resource overutilization, or misbehavior of certain SQL queries), the service immediately notifies you and provides diagnostic information, details on the extent of the problem, and intelligent recommendations to quickly resolve the issue.</description></item></channel></rss>