<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data-Quality on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/data-quality/</link><description>Recent content in Data-Quality on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 19:58:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/data-quality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taming the Data Beast: How GenAI Tackles Data Quality Issues 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-genai-dqm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-genai-dqm/</guid><description>Taming the Data Beast: How GenAI Tackles Data Quality Issues Introduction:
In the age of big data, the foundation of every impactful decision rests on one crucial element: quality data. Yet, data often arrives messy, incomplete, and inconsistent, plaguing modern data platforms with significant challenges. That&amp;rsquo;s where GenAI, the transformative power of Generative Artificial Intelligence, comes in, offering a beacon of hope in the battle for data integrity. Data Quality Issues: The Hydra We Face:</description></item><item><title>Keeping the Data Stream Clean with AWS 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-dqm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-dqm/</guid><description>Keeping the Data Stream Clean: How AWS Data Quality Solutions Power Diverse Applications Introduction:
In today&amp;rsquo;s data-driven world, the adage &amp;ldquo;garbage in, garbage out&amp;rdquo; rings truer than ever. The quality of your data directly impacts the accuracy, efficiency, and ultimately, the success of your analytics and application development endeavors.
Recognizing this crucial link, AWS offers a comprehensive suite of data quality solutions, empowering organizations across various industries to harness the true potential of their data assets.</description></item></channel></rss>