<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Best-Practices on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/best-practices/</link><description>Recent content in Best-Practices on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 11:28:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/best-practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tips &amp; Tricks while working on Amazon Redshift 🛡️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/tips-tricks-redshift/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/tips-tricks-redshift/</guid><description>Tips &amp;amp; Tricks while working on Amazon Redshift Introduction
Amazon Redshift, known for its scalability and efficiency, provides a powerful solution for data warehousing. This post offers a comprehensive technical exploration of Amazon Redshift, discussing best practices and examples about table design, query performance, cluster management, cost control, data sharing, data governance and security.
Table Design
Distribution Styles:
Redshift supports EVEN, KEY, and ALL distribution styles. The appropriate distribution style, which governs how data gets distributed across nodes, can significantly impact query performance.</description></item><item><title>Key Considerations for Utilizing Amazon Kinesis Producer and Consumer Libraries🛡️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/kinesis-library-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/kinesis-library-best-practices/</guid><description>Key Considerations for Utilizing Amazon Kinesis Producer and Consumer Libraries Introduction
As real-time data processing becomes increasingly critical in modern tech ecosystems, AWS Kinesis Data Streams (KDS) has emerged as a go-to solution. Kinesis offers scalable and durable real-time data streaming, further complemented by two crucial libraries:
Kinesis Producer Library (KPL) and Kinesis Consumer Library (KCL). Additionally, Kinesis supports advanced data sharing mechanisms, allowing data streams to be consumed by multiple entities simultaneously.</description></item><item><title>How to set up a secure Terraform backend using Amazon S3 + DynamoDB? 🛡️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/best-practice-terraform-backend/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/best-practice-terraform-backend/</guid><description>How to set up a secure Terraform backend using Amazon S3 + DynamoDB Introduction
Managing infrastructure as code is crucial for modern DevOps practices, and Terraform has emerged as a powerful tool for achieving this. In this technical guide, we will delve into the best practices for configuring a Terraform backend using Amazon Web Services&amp;rsquo; S3 bucket and associated resources. Our aim is to equip you with the skills needed to establish a production-ready environment with sensible defaults.</description></item></channel></rss>