<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Strategy on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/strategy/</link><description>Recent content in Strategy on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 11:28:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Achieving Data Governance on AWS 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/achieving-data-governance-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/achieving-data-governance-on-aws/</guid><description>Achieving Data Governance on AWS Summary of Part 1
In Part 1 of our blog, we explored the fundamental concepts of data governance and how to achieve it on AWS. We discussed the importance of data governance for digital business success, the key roles involved, and how to align data governance with business initiatives. We also covered a comprehensive model for data governance, focusing on understanding, curating, and protecting data using AWS tools and services.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Data Governance and How to Achieve It on AWS 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/understanding-data-governance-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/understanding-data-governance-on-aws/</guid><description>Understanding Data Governance and How to Achieve It on AWS Introduction
What is Data Governance?
Data governance is the practice of managing data to ensure its availability, usability, integrity, and security within an organization. According to Gartner, by 2025, 80% of organizations seeking to scale digital businesses will fail because they do not take a modern approach to data and analytics governance. Data governance involves a set of processes, roles, policies, standards, and metrics that ensure the effective and efficient use of information to enable an organization to achieve its goals.</description></item></channel></rss>