<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Amwaa on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/amwaa/</link><description>Recent content in Amwaa on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 23:59:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/amwaa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Integrate Jfrog Artifactory with AWS Managed workflow for Apache Airflow 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrate-jfrog-with-amwa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrate-jfrog-with-amwa/</guid><description>Integrate Jfrog Artifactory with AWS Managed workflow for Apache Airflow Overview
When managing data pipelines and workflows in AWS Managed Apache Airflow, it&amp;rsquo;s often necessary to integrate with various external services for tasks such as downloading binaries, libraries, or other dependencies. JFrog Artifactory is a popular binary repository manager that allows you to securely store and manage artifacts. Integrating JFrog with AWS Managed Apache Airflow enables seamless and secure downloading of these artifacts, ensuring that your workflows can reliably access the necessary resources.</description></item><item><title>Integrate AWS Secret Manager with AWS Managed workflow for Apache Airflow 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrate-secret-with-amwa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrate-secret-with-amwa/</guid><description>Integrate AWS Secret Manager with AWS Managed workflow for Apache Airflow Overview
What is AWS Managed Apache Airflow?
AWS Managed Apache Airflow (MWAA) is a managed service that makes it easier to run and manage workflows built with Apache Airflow on AWS. Apache Airflow is an open-source tool used to programmatically author, schedule, and monitor workflows. With MWAA, AWS takes care of the operational aspects such as scaling, patching, and availability, allowing you to focus on building and managing your workflows.</description></item></channel></rss>