<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/data/</link><description>Recent content in Data on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 07:23:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Accelerate Your GenAI Adoption with a Zero-ETL Data Architecture 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/modern-zero-etl-genai/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/modern-zero-etl-genai/</guid><description>Accelerate Your GenAI Adoption with a Zero-ETL Data Architecture Introduction
In the rapidly evolving landscape of artificial intelligence, Generative AI (GenAI) stands out as a transformative force across various industries. Its ability to create original content—be it text, images, or even music—has the potential to redefine how businesses operate and innovate. However, the true power of GenAI is unlocked only when it is fed with high-quality, diverse, and accessible data. This is where a modern data strategy becomes essential.</description></item><item><title>Achieving Data Governance on AWS 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/achieving-data-governance-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/achieving-data-governance-on-aws/</guid><description>Achieving Data Governance on AWS Summary of Part 1
In Part 1 of our blog, we explored the fundamental concepts of data governance and how to achieve it on AWS. We discussed the importance of data governance for digital business success, the key roles involved, and how to align data governance with business initiatives. We also covered a comprehensive model for data governance, focusing on understanding, curating, and protecting data using AWS tools and services.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Data Governance and How to Achieve It on AWS 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/understanding-data-governance-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/understanding-data-governance-on-aws/</guid><description>Understanding Data Governance and How to Achieve It on AWS Introduction
What is Data Governance?
Data governance is the practice of managing data to ensure its availability, usability, integrity, and security within an organization. According to Gartner, by 2025, 80% of organizations seeking to scale digital businesses will fail because they do not take a modern approach to data and analytics governance. Data governance involves a set of processes, roles, policies, standards, and metrics that ensure the effective and efficient use of information to enable an organization to achieve its goals.</description></item><item><title>Speed Up Your Data Journey: Building with the AWS Data Solutions Framework 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-data-solutions-framework/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-data-solutions-framework/</guid><description>Speed Up Your Data Journey: Building with the AWS Data Solutions Framework Introduction
The cloud has revolutionized data management, offering on-demand scalability and a vast array of services for building robust data solutions. But navigating the complexities of AWS and architecting secure, efficient data pipelines can be time-consuming.
Unveiling the Framework&amp;rsquo;s Magic
Built on the AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK), DSF offers reusable constructs representing common data platform components like data lakes, data pipelines, and analytics environments.</description></item></channel></rss>