<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Re:invent on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/reinvent/</link><description>Recent content in Re:invent on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 10:29:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/reinvent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Airflow - from Zero to Hero</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/apache-airflow-devtron/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/apache-airflow-devtron/</guid><description>Apache Airflow - from Zero to Hero Overview
In this webinar, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the factors to consider, the difficulties to overcome while running a custom Orchestration tool at scale, and how Apache Airflow comes to the rescue.
To begin, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss what it means to run Airflow at a large scale. The constructs of the Airflow architecture, Scheduler procedures, and configuration options will then be thoroughly discussed.
After that, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how Amazon Managed Workflows for Apache Airflow (MWAA) helps simplify the complexity of open-source Apache Airflow and the additional security features it offers.</description></item><item><title>Recap of AWS re:Invent 2022 - App Integration, Serverless &amp; DevSecOps Highlights 📜</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/reinvent2022-recap-devops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/reinvent2022-recap-devops/</guid><description>Recap of AWS re:Invent 2022 - App Integration, Serverless &amp;amp; DevSecOps Highlights Overview
AWS re:Invent 2022 is in the bag! The 11th iteration of the annual cloud conference saw more than 50,000 partners and customers descend on Las Vegas in person, accompanied by more than 300,000 remote attendees.
The world is asynchronous. The world is event-driven. — Dr. Werner Vogels, CTO, Amazon.com It required a world stage to propagate asynchrony and event-driven architecture in our modern era of cloud computing.</description></item><item><title>Recap of AWS re:Invent 2022 - Data &amp; Analytics Highlights 📜</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/reinvent2022-recap-dna/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/reinvent2022-recap-dna/</guid><description>Recap of AWS re:Invent 2022 - Data &amp;amp; Analytics Highlights Overview
AWS re:Invent 2022 is in the bag! The 11th iteration of the annual cloud conference saw more than 50,000 partners and customers descend on Las Vegas in person, accompanied by more than 300,000 remote attendees. The event featured excellent keynote speakers, product announcements, training and certification opportunities, hands-on technical sessions, and more. I was thrilled to witness all of the fun, fully embracing AWS CEO Adam Selipsky&amp;rsquo;s message that now is the perfect time to &amp;ldquo;lean in harder&amp;rdquo; to help clients accelerate their journey to the cloud.</description></item><item><title>AWS re:Invent 2022 - Reinvent your business with an AWS modern data strategy</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/aws-re-invent-2022---pex308/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/webinar/aws-re-invent-2022---pex308/</guid><description>AWS re:Invent 2022 - Reinvent your business with an AWS modern data strategy (PEX308) Overview
AWS can help organizations quickly get answers from data by providing mature and integrated analytics services ranging from cloud data warehouses to serverless data lakes. Join this session to learn about AWS modern data architecture and how AWS analytics services can help your customers navigate data challenges, optimize analytics processes, and deliver insights to their businesses faster.</description></item></channel></rss>