<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Overview on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/overview/</link><description>Recent content in Overview on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 23:59:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/overview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Debugging Lambda Functions with Amazon Q 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/debug-lambda-amazon-q/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/debug-lambda-amazon-q/</guid><description>Debugging Lambda Functions with Amazon Q Introduction
What is AWS Lambda?
AWS Lambda is a serverless compute service that enables you to run applications and services without provisioning or managing servers. It automatically handles the underlying compute resources, allowing you to focus on your code and scale effortlessly. What is Amazon Q?
Amazon Q generates code, tests, debugs, and has multistep planning and reasoning capabilities that can transform and implement new code generated from developer requests.</description></item><item><title>Tips &amp; Tricks for Optimizing Amazon OpenSearch: Performance and Cost Efficiency 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-opensearch-best-practice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-opensearch-best-practice/</guid><description>Tips &amp;amp; Tricks for Optimizing Amazon OpenSearch: Performance and Cost Efficiency Amazon OpenSearch Service (formerly Amazon Elasticsearch Service) is a powerful tool for search, log analytics, and real-time application monitoring. However, as with any cloud service, improper management can lead to performance issues and unexpected costs. Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore best practices to get the most out of OpenSearch while keeping your costs under control.
Rightsizing Your Infrastructure
Instance Selection: Use the latest generation instance types.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Bedrock Agent - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-agent/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-agent/</guid><description>Amazon Bedrock Agent - Overview Introduction
What is Amazon Bedrock?
Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies like Stability AI, Anthropic, and Meta via a single API. It also provides the broad capabilities needed to build Generative AI applications with security, privacy, and responsible AI. Since Amazon Bedrock is serverless, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to manage any infrastructure, and you can securely integrate and deploy Generative AI capabilities into your applications using the AWS services you already know.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-kb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-bedrock-kb/</guid><description>Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Bases - Overview Introduction
What is Amazon Bedrock? Amazon Bedrock is a fully managed service that offers a choice of high-performing foundation models (FMs) from leading AI companies like Stability AI, Anthropic, and Meta via a single API. It also provides the broad capabilities needed to build Generative AI applications with security, privacy, and responsible AI. Since Amazon Bedrock is serverless, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to manage any infrastructure, and you can securely integrate and deploy Generative AI capabilities into your applications using the AWS services you already know.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Lightsail - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-lightsail/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-lightsail/</guid><description>Amazon Lightsail - Overview Introduction
What is Amazon Lightsail?
Amazon Lightsail is the easiest way to get started with Amazon Web Services (AWS) for anyone who needs to build websites or web applications. It includes everything you need to launch your project quickly—instances (virtual private servers), container services, managed databases, content delivery network (CDN) distributions, load balancers, SSD-based block storage, static IP addresses, DNS management of registered domains, and resource snapshots (backups) - for a low, predictable monthly price.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Redshift ML - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-rs-serverless-ml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-rs-serverless-ml/</guid><description>Amazon Redshift ML - Overview Introduction
Amazon Redshift ML makes it easy for data analysts and database developers to create, train, and apply machine learning models using familiar SQL commands in Amazon Redshift data warehouses.
With Redshift ML, you can take advantage of Amazon SageMaker, a fully managed machine learning service, without learning new tools or languages. Simply use SQL statements to create and train Amazon SageMaker machine learning models using your Redshift data and then use these models to make predictions.</description></item><item><title>Keeping the Data Stream Clean with AWS 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-dqm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-dqm/</guid><description>Keeping the Data Stream Clean: How AWS Data Quality Solutions Power Diverse Applications Introduction:
In today&amp;rsquo;s data-driven world, the adage &amp;ldquo;garbage in, garbage out&amp;rdquo; rings truer than ever. The quality of your data directly impacts the accuracy, efficiency, and ultimately, the success of your analytics and application development endeavors.
Recognizing this crucial link, AWS offers a comprehensive suite of data quality solutions, empowering organizations across various industries to harness the true potential of their data assets.</description></item><item><title>Embracing AWS Zero ETL for Enhanced Data-Driven Decision Making 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-zero-etl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-zero-etl/</guid><description>Embracing AWS Zero ETL for Enhanced Data-Driven Decision Making Introduction
In the modern data-centric world, swift and informed decision-making is crucial for business success. AWS (Amazon Web Services) provides an innovative solution to expedite data-driven decisions through its Zero ETL (Extract, Transform, Load) approach. This blog delves into the essence of Zero ETL, its benefits, and a practical example showcasing its role in expediting data-driven decisions. Understanding Zero ETL
Zero ETL represents a data integration method that forgoes the conventional ETL process, which typically involves extracting data from various sources, transforming it to a structured format, and loading it into a data warehouse for analysis.</description></item><item><title>Unlocking the Full Potential of AWS re:Invent 2023 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-reinvent-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-reinvent-2023/</guid><description>Unlocking the Full Potential of AWS re:Invent 2023 1. Introduction:
AWS re:Invent 2023, hosted by Amazon Web Services (AWS), stands as a pinnacle event in cloud computing. Since its inception in 2012, it has showcased the forefront of cloud technology. This comprehensive guide aims to assist attendees, whether they&amp;rsquo;re seasoned cloud experts or just embarking on their AWS journey, in making the most of the multifaceted experience at AWS re:Invent 2023.</description></item><item><title>Overview of Amazon Athena for Apache Spark 💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-athena-spark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-athena-spark/</guid><description>Overview of Amazon Athena for Apache Spark Introduction
Amazon Athena for Apache Spark provides interactive analytics under a second to analyze petabytes of data using open source spark framework. Interactive Spark applications start instantly and run faster with our optimized Spark runtime, so you spend more time on insights, not waiting for results. Build Spark applications using the expressiveness of Python with a simplified notebook experience in an Athena console or through Athena APIs.</description></item><item><title>Seamless Data Sharing Using Amazon Redshift 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-redshift-data-sharing-part1/</guid><description>Seamless Data Sharing Using Amazon Redshift Introduction
What is Amazon Redshift?
Amazon Redshift is a fast, fully managed, petabyte-scale cloud-based data warehouse service. It makes it simple and cost-effective to efficiently run your analytics workloads at scale. Amazon Redshift uses columnar storage (also known as columnstore) to store your data in columns instead of rows, which allows it to make more efficient use of storage space and compute resources than traditional row-oriented databases like MySQL or PostgreSQL.</description></item><item><title>Amazon EMR Serverless - Overview 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-serverless/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/amazon-emr-serverless/</guid><description>Amazon EMR Serverless - Overview Introduction
What is Amazon EMR?
Amazon EMR is a cloud big data platform running large-scale distributed data processing jobs, interactive SQL queries, and machine learning (ML) applications using open-source analytics frameworks such as Apache Spark, Apache Hive, and Presto. Understanding clusters and nodes A cluster is a collection of Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances. An instance in the cluster is called a node, and each node has role within the cluster, referred to as the node type.</description></item><item><title>Let's explore the working of AWS Application Migration Service 📦</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-application-migration-service/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-application-migration-service/</guid><description>AWS Application Migration Service Introduction
AWS Application Migration Service allows migrating the critical workloads to AWS avoiding any interference, or data leakage. With continuous block-level replication, automated machine conversion, and application stack orchestration, Application Migration Service simplifies the migration process and minimizes the chance for human error.
Whether we are moving to AWS or across regions within AWS, Application Migration Service simplicity the needs and provides the security measures require to win in today’s fast-paced digital era</description></item><item><title>Exploring Amazon Pinpoint💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-amazon-pinpoint/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-amazon-pinpoint/</guid><description>Amazon Pinpoint Introduction
Amazon Pinpoint is an AWS service which allow to occupy the customers across multiple messaging channels. We can leverage Amazon Pinpoint to send push notifications, emails, SMS text messages, and voice messages.
Amazon Pinpoint allows to send customer oriented messages with better experiences which strengths the association with the customers and reduce the agitate.
Amazon Pinpoint provides functionalities such as:
Marketing campaigns and journeys
Transactional messages
Analytics tools</description></item><item><title>Configure AWS Managed Service For Grafana 📉</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-managed-grafana/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-managed-grafana/</guid><description>AWS Managed Service For Grafana Introduction
Amazon Managed Service for Grafana (AMG) is a completely managed service that allows defining query, relations, and depicts trends, logs, and traces for the applications from various sources like Amazon CloudWatch, Amazon Elasticsearch Service, Amazon Timestream, AWS IoT SiteWise, AWS X-Ray, and Amazon Managed Service for Prometheus (AMP) and provides plug-ins to popular open-source databases, third-party ISV monitoring tools, as well as other cloud services.</description></item><item><title>What is AWS Parameter Store? 🔑</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-parameter-store/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-parameter-store/</guid><description>AWS Systems Manager Parameter Store Introduction
AWS Systems Manager Parameter Store offers secure, hierarchical storage for configuration data management and secrets management. You can persist in things such as passwords, connection strings, Ec2 AMI IDs, and license as parameter values. Values can be persisted as plain text or encrypted data. You can refer to parameters in your scripts by providing the unique name that you mention while creating the parameter. How can Parameter Store benefit my organization?</description></item><item><title>Tool to assist AWS Well-Architected Framework ⌛</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/walkthrough-of-war-tool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/walkthrough-of-war-tool/</guid><description>WALKTHROUGH OF THE WELL-ARCHITECTED TOOL Introduction
AWS Well-Architected Framework assists architects to create secure, scalable, durable, and efficient workload and it consists of five foundational pillars Operational Excellence, Security, Reliability, Performance Efficiency, and Cost Optimization It is a repeatable framework that assists customers and partners to validate the architectures and design that can scale over time. The AWS WA Tool, which is free at no cost and available under AWS Management Console, provides a way to regularly validate your workloads, discover potential issues, and capture your improvements.</description></item></channel></rss>